不准这样  在我这里得守我的规矩
None of that. Not while you're under my roof!
什么
What?
就算我知道内幕
Look, just because I know about you two
也不代表我喜欢看你们亲热
doesn't mean I like looking at it.
你试镜不是还有一小时才结束吗
Aren't you supposed to be at an audition for an other hour?
很抱歉我不是黑人大妈
I'm sorry I'm not a middle-aged black woman.
而且还走错试镜场地
I'm also sorry if sometimes I go to the wrong audition.
如果要我假装不知道你们的事
Okay, look, if I have to pretend to I don't know about you two...
你们就得假装你们之间没什么
then you two are gonna have to pretend there's nothing to know about.
-好的  抱歉  -抱歉
- Okay. Sorry. - Sorry.
我听到了
I can hear that!
瑞秋还在上班
Rachel's at work.
我还是能听到
I can still hear you!
-你好  -嘿  那是什么
- Hello. - Hey. What's that?
我妈把外婆的传家宝
My mom sent me an family heirloom that once
寄给了我
belonged to my grandmother.
你们相信吗
Can you believe it?
一年前我连家人都没有
A year ago I didn't even have a family,
现在我竟然有祖传宝物
and now I have heirlooms for crying out loud.
天哪
Oh, God!
好软
Soft.
这是貂皮吗
Is this mink?
我妈为什么送我毛皮大衣
Why would my mother send me a fur?
她完全不了解我吗
Doesn't she know me but at all?
我已经有了非常好的大衣
Plus, I have a perfectly fine coat
而且没牺牲任何可怜的动物
that no innocent animal suffered to make!
只不过是九岁的菲律宾童工
Yeah, just some 9-year-old Filipino kids
为了时薪一毛二卖命做的
who worked their fingers bloody for 12 cents an hour.
没这种事  我胡说的
That didn't happen, I made that up!
罗斯  你不能在这里贴广告
Ross, Ross, you can't put up flyers in here.
为什么  别人都可以
How come? Everybody else does.
你不可以
You can't.
那是什么东西
What is that?
我要处理掉一些东西
I'm getting rid of some things.
这是你全部家当
This is all of your things.
对  没错
Yes, it is.
这很好  艾蜜莉说我们应该都换成新的
It's good. Emily thinks we should get all new stuff.
只属于我们的  全新的东西
Stuff that's just ours. Together. Brand new.
所以这是
So basically, this is a
"瑞秋碰过的家具"大拍卖
getting-rid-of-everything-Rachel-ever-touched sale.
摸过  用过  坐过  睡过的
Touched, used, sat on, slept on...
我全买了
I'll take it all.
罗斯  你不反对吗
Ross, you're okay with that?
只要一切顺着艾蜜莉
Look, if I can just do what Emily wants and
等她来纽约后就没事了
get her to New York, I'm sure everything will be fine.
但是这么做太极端了吧
Okay, but don't you think this is a little extreme?
想想我做过的事情  还能怪她吗
After what I did, can you blame her?
我的天  你已经算轻松了
Oh my God! You got off easy!
我朋友席薇的丈夫在床上喊错名字后
When my friend Silvie's husband said someone else's name in bed,
她诅咒他并把他的小弟弟弄成了绿色
she cursed him and turned his thingy green.
他这是做什么
What is he doing?
艾蜜莉觉得罗斯的家具会染上瑞秋的虱子吗
Emily thinks Ross' furniture has got Rachel cooties?
别激动  乔伊
Calm down, Joey.
不  事情都搞得乱七八糟了
No! Everything's gettin' all messed up, y'know?
艾蜜莉不准罗斯见瑞秋
Emily won't let Ross see Rachel.
可是我们会继续见瑞秋
we're not gonna stop seeing Rachel,
因此  罗斯再也不能见我们
hence Ross stops seeing us!
我讨厌这样  一切都变了
I hate this. Everything's changing.
我们失去了罗斯  乔伊还会用"因此"
I know we're losing Ross. Joey said "hence."
我也不高兴  但是如果罗斯能开心
I'm not happy about this either, but if Ross says he's happy...
我们就不该说出
then we're just gonna have to keep
自己对艾蜜莉的不满
our feelings about Emily to ourselves.
你同意吗
Are you cool with that?
不
No!
不过你们知道  我是演员
But, you know, I'm an actor.
我可以装得无所谓
I'll act cool.
老天  我怕死储藏室了
Ohh, whoa God! Storage rooms give me the creeps!
莫妮卡  快点  亲爱的
Monica, come on please hurry up honey! Please?
瑞秋  你要吃小圆松饼
Rachel, if you want the little round waffles,
就得让我先找到煎盘
you gotta have to wait until I find the little waffle iron.
我想吃小圆松饼
I want the little round waffles.
找到了
Here it is!
就在杀虫剂下面
Right underneath the can of bug bomb.
看来放置厨具最好的地方
I wonder if the best place to put something that cooks food
就是毒药下面
is underneath the can of poison?
知道吗  我吃吐司好了
Okay. You know what? I'll have toast.
我的天
Oh my god!
喷他  喷他
Fog him! Fog him!
我不知道该如何处置这件毛皮大衣
I don't know what I'm gonna do about this coat.
可以给我
I'll take it.
好主意
That might work.
你们觉得如何
All right. What do you think?
五分钟后换你上台  明妮莉小姐
You're on in five, Ms. Minnelli.
不  只是有点突然
No, it's just a bit sudden.
非常好  我也全力赞成
It's great, okay? I am totally onboard.
我也爱你  好  再见
I love you too. All right, bye.
怎么了  罗斯
What's the matter, Ross?
没事  其实
Nothing. No, actually...
是好消息
...great news!
我刚跟艾蜜莉通完电话
I just got off the phone with Emily
看来我要搬家了
and it looks like I'm moving to a new apartment.
为什么
Why?
她认为  而且我也同意
Her thought is, and I agree...
既然要换新家具  干脆换间公寓
...fresh new furniture, why not a fresh new apartment?
她表弟有间房子要转租
Her cousin has a place to sublet.
一边可以看到河  一边可以看到哥伦比亚县
It's got a view of the river on one side and Columbia on the other.
那是郊区  要转三次火车
That's way uptown! That's three trains away...
太棒了
...which is great!
我喜欢搭火车
I love to ride that rail.
你真的同意吗
So you're really okay with this?
是的  离上班地点是有点远
Yes! Yes! I mean it's-it's kinda far from work,
但是我坐车时可以做很多事
...but I'll get so much done on the commute.
她算是送了我一份大礼  那就是时间
I've been given the gift of time.
有意思  上次圣诞节我得到很多空间
That's so funny. Last Christmas I got the gift of space.
两样加起来就有个小宇宙了
We should get them together and make a continuum.
现在还要搬家
Now he's moving?
艾蜜莉到底想对他怎么样
Man, what is Emily doing to him?
他又不在这里
He's not even here!
大家听我们说
You guys! You guys!
我们刚刚去储藏室
We were, we were just in the storage area
看到一个很可怕的人
and we saw this really creepy man!
眼神凶残  全身毛茸茸
It was this crazy-eyed, hairy beast-man.
就像大脚怪或是喜马拉雅山雪人
It was like a Big Foot or a yeti or something.
他拿着斧头向我们走来
And he came at us with an axe,
瑞秋只好拿杀虫剂喷他
so Rachel had to use a bug bomb on him!
我拉开拉环拼命喷他
I pulled the tab and I just fogged his yeti ass.
-深色头发  满脸胡须  -是的
- Like, dark hair, bushy beard? - Yeah.
你们喷的是丹尼
Yeah, you fogged Danny.
拜托  才没有喷丹尼
Please! We did not fog Danny.
丹尼是谁
Who's Danny?
丹尼刚搬到楼下
Danny just moved in downstairs.
他去了安第斯山四个月才刚回国
Yeah, he just got back from like this four-month trek in the Andes.
他人很好
Nice fella.
什么人很好  每次我们喷谁
He's nice. He's nice. You know, you always...
你就帮他说话
...stick up for the people we fog.
-什么事  -你好
- Yeah? - Hi.
你大概不记得了  我们就是之前喷你的人
You might not remember us, but we're the girls that fogged you.
我们很抱歉喷到你
We're really sorry we fogged you.
好的
Okay.
我们只是要告诉你  我们不是故意的
Just so you know, we didn't mean to fog you.
我们以为你是雪人或者怪物
We actually thought you were like a yeti or something.
好的
Okay.
什么事
Yes?
抱歉打扰你
Sorry to bother you,
但我们无法接受你接受道歉的态度
but I don't think we can accept your acceptance of our apology.
听起来一点也不真心
It just doesn’t really seem like you mean it.
好的
Okay.
这家伙真没礼貌
That guy is so rude!
没错  他哪里有病
Really! What is with that guy?
换作我喷你  你早就原谅我了
You'd forgive me if I fogged you.
其实你有喷到一点点
You did, a little bit.
天啊  亲爱的  我很抱歉
Oh, my God, honey. I'm so sorry.
-我完全不介意  -真的吗
- I totally forgive you. - Really?
你知道我那个开火葬场的朋友克里斯吧
So listen. You know my friend Chris who owns the crematorium?
火葬场克里斯  当然知道
Crematorium Chris? Sure.
他说他愿意免费帮我烧毛皮大衣
He said he would cremate my fur coat for free...
只要我介绍下个挂掉的朋友去那里火化就行
...if I bring in the next person I know who dies.
天啊
Oh, my God!
天啊  好漂亮的毛皮大衣
Oh, my God. Look at these pelts!
别太喜欢  她要烧掉
Don't get too attached. She's having it cremated.
菲比  亲爱的  我知道你怪怪的
Uhh, Phoebe, honey, honey, I know you're quirky
大家平时也欣赏你这点
and I get a big kick out of it, we all do actually.
但是你毁掉这么棒的大衣
But if you destroy a coat like this...
实在是有违天理
...that is like a crime against nature.
说错了  是时尚不容
Not nature. Fashion!
这叫做时尚
This is fashion?
原来对你来说  尸体就是时尚
So to you, death is fashion?
实在有意思
That's really funny.
接下来菲比
Here's Phoebe...
为各位展示最流行的毛茸茸尸体
...sporting cutting-edge hairy carcass...
这些动物死在寒冷俄罗斯的捕兽夹下
...from, you know, the steel traps of wintry Russia.
你们真认为好看吗
You really think this looks good?
因为我觉得不赖
Because I do!
我知道  我也想你  真希望快点见到你
I know, I miss you too. I can't wait to see you.
我爱你  再见
I love you. Bye.
这是什么  石头吗
What is in here, rocks?
不  我收集的化石样本
No, it's my collection of fossil samples.
就是石头嘛
So, rocks.
我一定会想念这里的
I'm really gonna miss this apartment.
小本就在那边学会走路的
You know, Ben took his first steps right over there.
记不记得我上次撞到这里
Remember when I ran into this thing and
然后昏倒了
it kinda knocked me out a little?
我很喜欢这间公寓
I love this place.
老实说  我真希望别搬家
To tell the truth, I wish I didn't have to move.
你的意思是  搬家让你不开心
Are you saying that you're not entirely happy about this?
如果艾蜜莉给我选择的机会
If Emily gave me a choice...
你本来就有机会
You do have a choice!
罗斯  你为什么要听她的  你疯了吗
Ross, why are you listening to her? Are you crazy?
怎么了
What?
艾蜜莉这些要求太过分  她根本就是...
It's not right what Emily wants you to do. She's totally...
不要再掐我了
Stop pinching me!
你们都说只要罗斯快乐
Look, now you guys said I only had to keep my mouth shut
我就不该说  对吗
as long as Ross was happy, right?
可是他刚说他不是很开心
He just told me that he's not entirely happy.
这是怎么回事
What's going on?
我们都讨厌艾蜜莉
We all hate Emily!
不
No!
不  罗斯  我们不讨厌艾蜜莉
No, Ross, we do not hate Emily.
我们只是认为你为了讨她开心
We just think that you're having to sacrifice...
牺牲的太多
...a whole lot to make her happy.
没错
Yeah.
大家都认为她有点不可理喻
We just think that maybe she's being a little unreasonable.
对  就是不可理喻
Yes, unreasonable.
不可理喻
Unreasonable?
等你们谁结婚了  我们再讨论这个问题吧
How about we have this conversation when one of you guys gets married!
你们根本不知道如何维持婚姻
You have no idea what it takes to make a marriage work.
婚姻就是互相妥协  永远都会开心吗  不会
It's about compromise. Do you always like it? No.
但是你愿意吗  愿意
Do you do it? Yes.
因为婚姻不是只有欢笑  快乐  梦幻
Because it's not all laughing, happy, candy in the sky...
一天到晚上咖啡馆喝咖啡
drinking coffee at Central Perk all the time!
婚姻是现实生活  知道吗
It's real life, okay?
婚姻只适合成年人
It's what grownups do.
他说得有道理
I think he's right.
你们泡咖啡馆的时间太长了
You guys hang out at the coffee house way too much.
-我对罗斯很抱歉  -我知道
- I feel so guilty about Ross. - I know.
我觉得似乎都怪我
I kind of feel like it's my fault.
似乎
Kind of?
要不是你大嘴巴  也不会有这种下场
If you just kept this to yourself none of this would've happened.
我最近知道的秘密太多
I'm keeping so many things to myself these days,
总有说漏嘴的时候
something was bound to slip out!
你说出真实想法其实很勇敢
I think it's very brave what you said.
我坐不住了  我得去走走
I can't sit here anymore. I have to walk places.
菲比  你怎么还穿那件大衣
Pheebs, what are you doing with the coat?
你不是很关心动物的权益吗
How about the whole animal rights thing?
我最近看了一些书  告诉你们
I've been reading up, and for your information...
貂不是好动物
...minks aren't very nice.
好吧  我承认  我喜欢这件大衣
Okay, I admit it. I love this coat, okay?
这是裹在我身上最棒的东西
It's the best thing I ever had wrapped around me,
菲尔·亨特利都不够好
including Phil Huntley.
还记得菲尔·亨特利吗  他帅呆了
Remember Phil Huntley? He was fine.
你好
Hi.
-原来你比较喜欢短发  -什么
- So you like the short hair better? - What?
雪人  你是丹尼
Yeti? Danny?
我得剪头发因为
I had to cut my hair to get rid of...
杀虫剂的味道洗不掉
...the fogger smell.
抱歉  我本来绝对不会乱喷的
Listen, I'm so sorry. I would have never fogged you...
要不是你的样子实在...
...if you hadn't looked so... You know...
当然  有些人只会以貌取人
Absolutely. Some people are just into appearances.
什么
What?
无所谓
It's cool.
等等  什么无所谓
No-no-no! That is not cool!
你根本不认识我
You don't even know me.
你提着一堆购物袋  还有购物目录
Come on, you got the shopping bags and the Sack's catalog.
你以为这样就能看透我吗
So from that you think you've got me all figured out?
才怪
Well, you don't.
搞不好我的袋子里装满给贫困儿童的玩具
You know, I could have toys for underprivileged kids in here.
是吗
Do you?
如果他们喜欢拿紧身裤当玩具的话
You know, if kids like to play with capri pants.
好的
Okay.
不准你再说这话  很刺耳
Stop saying that. I hate that!
好的
Okay.
好吧  我当时是以貌取人了
Fine. I judged you. I made a snap judgment.
可是你也一样  而且更糟糕
But you did it too, and you are worse
你只相信愚蠢的第一印象
because you are sticking to your stupid snap judgement!
甚至都不肯
You can't even open up your mind
反省自己对不对
for a second to see if you might be wrong!
你有什么资格说别人
What does that say about you?
对面那家披萨店好吃吗
That pizza place across the street any good?
什么
What?
我饿了  你要不要去吃披萨
I'm hungry. You want some pizza?
你还想骂人也可以继续吼
You can keep yelling if there's more.
好的  好的
Okay. Okay.
不准说这话  很刺耳
Stop saying that. I hate that.
罗斯
Ross.
-你还在生我们的气吗  -是的
- Are you still mad at us? - Yep.
很好  我写了一首"很抱歉"的歌
Good! We have an "I'm Sorry" song.
告诉你们  我现在心情不好
You know what? I'm not in the mood.
听着  罗斯
Look, Ross.
我很难过  你的生活发生巨大改变
I feel really bad. You're going through all this stuff...
我却乱讲话
...and I just acted like a jerk.
-我们都很抱歉  -你说出歌词了
- We are so sorry. - You're kinda stepping on the song.
我们实在太离谱了  其实我们都是支持你的
We were way out of line, all right? We totally support you.
无论你做什么决定  我们都赞成
Whatever you decide, whatever you do.
歌词被你们说完了
Now you're just taking lines out of the song.
我已经够难过了
This is hard enough, okay?
现在真的很需要你们
I really need you guys right now.
没错  所以我们才要
Yes, exactly! And that's why...
你今晚过来吧
Why don't you come over tonight,
我为你煮几道你爱吃的菜
and I'll make your favorite dinner.
来吧
Come on.
好的
Okay.
谢谢你们
Thanks, you guys.
菲比  你身上这件是毛皮大衣吗
Pheebs are you wearing fur?
别再大惊小怪了
Let's get some perspective, people.
这又不是用导盲犬的皮做的
It's not like I'm wearing a seeing-eye dog coat!
罗斯  我知道今天我为什么
You know, Ross, I think I kind of understand
突然爆发了
why I lost it today.
是吗
You do, huh?
你知道
You see...
我是个演员
...I'm an actor, right?
所以我的情绪比较丰富
So I got to keep my emotions right at the surface.
生活中要处理的问题太多了  你懂吗
I got a lot of balls in the air, you know?
我这种人的生活实在不容易
It's tough. Guys like me,
到处流浪  孤孤单单
you wander around, you're alone.
你胡说什么
What are you talking about?
我也不知道
I'm not sure.
回来了  你刚上哪去了
Look at you! Where have you been?
我去吃披萨
I went to have pizza.
跟丹尼一起
With Danny.
-怎么可能  -那个雪人很会讨女生欢心
- How did that happened? - That yeti is one smooth talker.
希望你不是太饱  晚餐快好了
I hope you're not full. Dinner's almost ready.
我还是回房间去好了
Yeah, y'know I-I think I'm just gonna hang out in my room.
为什么
Why?
拜托  各位
Come on, you guys!
要是艾蜜莉知道我跟你一起吃饭
If Emily knew I was here having dinner with you,
她会抓狂的  你知道的
she'd flip out. You know it.
没关系  我不介意
It's okay. I really don't mind.
等等  你留下来吧
Wait, wait. You know what? Just stay.
拜托
Please.
我希望你留下来
It would mean a lot for me if you stay.
罗斯  我
Ross, I just...
瑞秋  拜托你  跟我们一起吃饭吧
Rachel, please, just have dinner with us!
乔伊  没事的  别激动
Okay. Okay. Joey, it's okay. Settle down.
对不起  抱歉  抱歉
All right. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
瑞秋  我是演员
You see, Rach, I'm an actor.
看  丑裸男又出现了
Hey, look! Ugly Naked Guy's back.
我们好久没看到他了
We haven't seen him in so long.
天啊  我真想念这个死胖子
Oh, God! I really missed that fat bastard.
这可真奇怪  我刚意识到
This is so weird. I just realized this
这可能是大家最后一次在一起玩了
might be the last time we'll all be hanging out together.
他似乎也知道了
It's almost as if he knew.
我来接
I'll get it.
喂  嗨  艾蜜莉
Hello. Hi, Emily.
他在这里  你等等
Yeah, you tracked him down. Hold on one second.
对  我们正在吃饭
Yeah, we're just having dinner.
好  你等等
Sure, hold on.
她想跟大家打招呼  稍等
She wants to say hi. Hold on.
嗨  艾蜜莉
Hi, Emily!
大家好
Hello, everyone.
都有谁在啊
So who am I saying hello to?
我不知道这里有谁
Well, I don't know about who's here...
不过瑞秋肯定不在
but I can tell you for damn sure who’s not here and that's Rachel!!
最好是这样  罗斯应该很清楚了
I should hope not- Ross knows better than that by now-
你知道吗  其实瑞秋也在
You know what? Rachel is here.
她也在
She's there?
对  她在那边
Oh, yeah, there she is!
是的  她在这里
Yeah, she's here.
罗斯  切掉免提
Ross, take me off speakerphone.
你怎么可以这样对我
How could you do this to me?
我以为我已经把瑞秋的事说得够清楚了
I thought I made my feelings about Rachel perfectly clear.
艾蜜莉  我只是跟朋友吃饭
Emily, I'm just having dinner with my friends, okay?
很明显你就是喜欢跟她粘在一起
You obviously can't keep away from her.
艾蜜莉  你太夸张了
Emily, that's ridiculous.
我愿意为你搬家
Look, I'm moving for you.
愿意为你不见朋友
I'm cutting friends out of my life for you.
求求你赶快搭飞机来纽约  好吗
Please, just get on the plane and come to New York, okay?
你会知道我只想跟你在一起
You’ll see you're the only person I want to be with.
我过去之后就不会这么紧张了
I'll feel better when I'm there,
可以随时知道你在哪里
and I can know where you are all the time.
你不可能永远随时掌握我的行踪
You can't know where I am all the time.
如果你不信任我  我们的婚姻永远不会幸福
This marriage will never work if you don't trust me.
你说得对
You're right.
那么  你能相信我吗
So, can you trust me?
不相信
No.
好像很顺利
I think it's going okay.
他好像在微笑
Looks like he's smiling.
你怎么知道  你只能看到他的后脑勺
How can you tell? You can only see the back of his head!
当然看得出来
You can totally tell!
你们看
Here, look, watch me.
微笑
Smile.
皱眉  微笑
Frown. Smile.
皱眉
Frown.
微笑
Smile.
我想就这样了
I guess that's it.
怎么了  怎么回事
Why? What happened?
我的婚姻完了
My marriage is over.
看看你  全身发抖
Look at you, you're shivering.
给你
Here.
罗斯  有什么我们能做的吗
Ross, is there anything we can do?
有
Yeah,
帮我跟甘瑟要回家具
you can help me get my furniture back from Gunther.
别再折磨我了
Okay, stop tormenting me!
这是貂皮  貂很坏  而且貂讨厌松鼠
This is mink, okay? They're mean, and they hate squirrels.
很多貂可能都希望被做成貂皮大衣
And y'know, okay, most of these probably wanted to be coats!
好的  我知道了
Fine. No, I get it.
拿去
Here.
给你
You take it.
高兴了吧  我快冷死了
Are you happy now? I'm cold!